You've got quite the nerve to pick a quarrel with me, Giolio Comanche, the Silver Alchemist.
However...
You're pretty good to get out of that with only a scratch.
Only a scratch?
Drawn by a landscape as white as snow,
Masshiro na keshiki ni ima sasowarete
I'm headed toward an unseen world.
Boku wa yuku yo mada minu sekai e
I've been traveling while lost
Maigo no mama tabi shiteita
Under this gray sky.
Nezumiiro no sora no shita
Every day with new maps, stained with my many dreams.
Higawari no chizu ikutsumo no yume ga nijindeita
I wonder if someday,
Itsuka wa sa
Even with these tiny steps of mine,
Chippoke na boku no kono hohaba demo
I'll be able to travel beyond those clouds.
Ano kumo no mukou made yukeru kana
I put on a bold front.
Tsuyogatte
End up hurting myself.
Kizutsuita
I feel empty inside.
Kokoro sukashita youni
It's started to rain,
Furidashita
And the raindrops
Amatsubu tachi ga
Began to repeat their scattered reflections.
Ranhansha kurikaesu
These straight rays of light
Massugu na hikari ga
Start to cross one another.
Kousa shite
And without telling anyone where they're headed,
Yakusaki mo tsugenumama
Across the endless distances,
Doko made mo
They pass through all matter.
Tsukinukeru
I burn these faint afterimages onto my eyes.
Awai zanzou ryoume ni yakitsukete
Under this sky,
Kono sora no shita
Wherever I am,
Donna toko ni itemo
I should be able to reach
Todoku hazu nanda
The unseen world.
Mada minu sekai e
Who the hell is that?
Master, you're back!
I'm asking who the hell is that?!
Nice to meet you! I'm May Chang!
The Envoy from
the East
When I was unconscious on the roadside, I was saved by Sir Yoki, your master.
My master?
You're feeling better now, right? Then get out of here.
What do you want?
Allow me to seal your wound.
What?! It healed?!
It's called Eastern Alchemy, from the nation of Xing.
Xing?
Yeah! According to her, she crossed
the great desert of the east all by herself.
How stupid can you get?
I didn't cross it by myself!
I had a companion with me!
Companion? Oh, you mean that little thing?
Yes! Her name is Shao May!
This is... Eastern Alchemy, is it not?
A technique comprised of understanding and utilizing the veins of the dragon, power that runs through the earth...
This tattoo is used to draw power from our Eastern Alchemy.
My older brother studied both
Eastern Alchemy and Western Alchemy.
This tattoo is the outcome of his research.
Oh my! Your brother must be a really talented individual!
I have no idea what you two are talking about,
but since your wounds are all healed up, we can go back to Central now, right?
If that's the case, I'll get ready right away!
Hey! We told you to get out of here!
We're not going on a trip, you know!
I'm serious, too!
That immortal crap you were talking about earlier?
There's no way something like that could exist.
But it does! That's the reason why I-
Shut up! Brats like you should be on the playgr-
Immortality couldn't be achieved through Eastern Alchemy.
But maybe with its Western counterpart...
That's why I must meet that man I keep hearing stories about!
Blonde hair, golden eyes, wearing a red coat so elegantly...
A genius alchemist that saves people in a splendid manner...
Sir Edward Elric!
What should we do, Master?
I couldn't care less.
What's wrong, Black Hayate?
You don't want to be walking alone at this hour...
It's quite dangerous because...
...you could be attacked by me, Barry the Chopper!
What the hell was that for?!
Dammit! In that case...
...what do you think of this?!
W-Why aren't you shocked at all?
I know someone who's sort of like you.
Like me? Alphonse what's-his-name?
You know Alphonse?
So you're a friend of his, eh?
But I must say, lady...
...you're really strong!
The Philosopher's Stone.
I wouldn't have guessed
Research Laboratory 5 was involved in its refining.
There's a possibility the upper echelon of the military also has something to do with it.
And ones by the name of Lust and Envy...
Are they the ones who turned you into that?
No, this was done by the scientists.
They pulled my soul out of my body.
We might be able to find out who instructed
the experiments if we interrogate the scientists...
That can't be done.
None of them are left. They were also used as ingredients for the stone.
That way none of the information gets leaked. Two birds with one stone.
I wonder if this means they don't need to create any more stones?
Last question for you.
Are you the one who murdered the military officer about a month ago in a phone booth at Central?
I don't even know what you're talking about!
Was he cut up?
No...
I'll take your word for it.
Yo, Miss Winry!
How are you doing on this fine day?
Ed! Al!
What brings you here all of a sudden?
Geez...
Even Paninya has picked up a job and is working seriously...
Paninya?
Yup.
She stopped pickpocketing, and now she fixes roofs and does all sorts of high-altitude constructions.
Wow...
And what about you two?
Any progress at all?
Well, we're taking the long way, but...
We're slowly making our way... I guess.
Well, that's good to hear.
There! Temporary repairs complete.
Thanks, Winry!
I don't have enough parts right now to fix it up completely, so bear with that for now.
All right...
I'll go buy them right away, so could you go kill some time?
But what's there to do?
There are only automail shops here...
Al.
Brother...
What, did you find a cat or something?
Yeah.
I'm alive!
You guys saved my life! Thanks!
Oh, and thanks for the food!
Never said I'd pay for it.
Don't mind such a small thing!
Don't say small!
To be cared for in a foreign land... I'm so thankful.
"Foreign land"? Are you not from this country?
Yep! I came from Xing!
Xing...
That great nation to the east?
That's right! Crossing that desert felt like walking through hell...
But why did you take that route?
I wanted to see the Xerxes ruins.
Xerxes?
I heard there's nothing there.
Just a bit of research.
I came to this country for
Eastern Alchemy-related research, too.
Eastern Alchemy?
Oh right, you just call it alchemy in this country, don't you?
The alchemy in our country is a skill that is used predominantly for medical purposes.
Different customs, I guess.
It's mostly used for war in our country.
Skirmishes are still ongoing on the border with Aerugo to the south and Creta to the west.
And there's still the great nation of Drachma up north, too.
There is a non-aggression pact, but the only reason they don't bother to attack us is because Mt. Briggs is in the way.
Our relations aren't looking too good.
Such a scary country to be in...
This country's been so military-focused ever since King Bradley became the Führer President.
But I'm really curious.
About this Eastern Alchemy that's used for healing.
Me, too.
Oh, could you guys be alchemists?
Yeah.
I'm Edward Elric, a State Alchemist.
I'm his younger brother, Alphonse Elric.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Ling Yao!
The pleasure is mine.
Hey Ling, could you explain your Eastern Alchemy to us in detail?
Can't!
I'm not an alchemist.
What the hell did you come to research if you're not an alchemist?!
Just a little something.
You guys might know something about it...
The Philosopher's Stone.
I really want it...
Do you know anything about it?
Nope.
Can't say I do.
Seems like you do.
Care to tell me?
What do you plan to use it for?
To find the way to gain immortality.
Care to tell me?
Immortality? How stupid.
I'm totally serious.
Besides...
This doesn't seem like the right attitude to have...
...when asking for a favor!
Brother!
You're going to retaliate, too?!
H-Hey!
What are they, acrobats?
Martial arts from Xing, maybe?
This might be tough...
But still...
Yeah...
They're nothing...
...when compared to our Master!
What's that?
And there they go.
Old man, can I get some dessert?
Sure!
Shit!
Dammit...
All of a sudden demanding information on philosopher's stones and immortality...
...and then picking a fight with us...
What the hell are you guys up to?!
You, and that thin-eyed bastard!
I hit him?
Oww...
This guy went nuts right after I called Ling a thin-eyed bastard...
I get it...
Oh! Long time no see, Paninya!
What the heck are you doing?
Well, I guess I can kind of see the situation...
Oh, Paninya, can I ask you for a favor?
How strange... I can't seem to sense a flow of energy from that armored man...
What's going on...
You thought you'd stand a chance if you added allies?!
You fool!
What's wrong? What's wrong?
I can read your moves now!
If his subordinate is like this, then I guess that
thin-eyed bastard isn't that big of a deal himself!
Just as I thought... This guy gets
all worked up when his master is insulted.
And when that happens...
Your attacks become simple and easy to read!
Well then, I guess it's about time you revealed your face!
A woman?!
To have an internally mounted cannon...
I can't take this country lightly.
Well, I guess that wasn't bad for my first try.
Alchemy...
You did this without a transmutation circle?!
Well, then...
I wonder if Brother is doing okay?
I went a little overboard...
What should I do...
Master Ling is going to scold me...
Come on, missy.
What the hell are you using in a town?
If it hadn't been me, you would have killed someone!
Bastard... You broke your arm?!
I chased rabbits all the time when I was a kid.
Traps are my specialty.
Brother!
Yo, Al.
Good work, everyone!
You... coming out like that!
Man, you guys are really strong.
How about it? Become my underlings and let's rule a country?
Quit daydreaming!
How about you go back-
There they are!
You guys sure destroyed a lot of our city.
I hope you plan to pay for it.
Don't forget to pay for all that food, too.
H-Hang on a sec!
All the repair and the meal costs should be for these guys...
I no really understand this country language!
Bye-bye!
Get back here!!!
Huh?
They got away!
That one, too?!
What should we do...
I'd like to fix it all, but I'm kind of...
It's all right, Brother... I'll do it.
Huh? You can do it without a transmutation circle now?
Yeah. I think it's because my memories of the truth returned to me.
Which means...
Alchemy Technique
Brother's Dignity
Height
Brother's
Dignity
Just leave the rest to me.
Brother's
Dignity
What's wrong, Brother?
We're back!
Hey, we meet again!
What are you sitting there drinking tea for?!
That's horrible! I thought we were friends...
Who are you calling a friend?
Do you know what we went through because of your two subordinates?!
I'll scold them later, so forgive us, yeah?
The girl is Ran Fan,
and the old man is Fu.
They're from a clan that's served my family for generations.
Don't be too angry at them.
You leech off of me for food and you have
two companions with you? You seem like a rich guy.
Well, I'm a prince, after all.
Huh?
Prince?
You?
A prince?!
Isn't this the part where you're supposed to be astonished?
Sorry, it was just too unexpected...
A guy who passes out from hunger and then leeches off of people for food... a prince?!
I won't allow you to speak ill of Master Ling...
You were here all along?
Well, I guess "prince" doesn't really mean much.
Since there are so many of us princes.
Xing is a nation made up of more than fifty different clans,
and the emperor reigns at the top of that.
And a daughter of the chief of each clan marries the emperor and bears a child.
The current emperor has
twenty-four sons and nineteen daughters.
And I'm twelfth in line for succession.
Forty-three kids?
Aren't there ever disputes over who becomes heir?
We're right in the middle of that.
The Emperor is in very poor health right now...
Each clan is getting worked up to curry favor with him, since this is the best time to do so...
Which is why I'm also...
Going to offer up immortality to gain his favor...
Correct!
So please, won't you tell me?
Information about the Philosopher's Stone.
Nope!
Philosopher's stones aren't tools to be used for promotion!
If you won't tell me, I'll follow you forever!
Don't!!!
I'm back!
There seemed to be a huge commotion on the main street, so I got kinda held up-
Why is it torn off?!
Seriously!
Every! Single! Time!!!
Young master!
You don't need to bow down to those lowlifes...
If one bow from me would do the job,
that'd be really cheap.
The fate of 500,000 people in the Yao clan is in my hands.
My image is the least of my concerns.
So, where are you planning on going next to break your automail?
Why do you assume I'm going to break it?
We're thinking of going to Central to look something up.
Huh? You're going to Central?!
I want to go, too!
What for?
To give my regards to Mr. Hughes!
But don't you have work to do, Winry?
Not a problem at all, Winry.
You need to take a breather every now and then.
Really?! Thank you so much, Mr. Garfield!
Well then, I guess...
We're all headed for Central!
Yep!
It'll be quite a trip! I'm so excited!
You're not coming!!!
She came along anyway, didn't she?
Oh yeah, I still don't know your name, Master.
Won't you tell me already?
Ishbalans consider their names gifts from God and speak of them with honor.
My my... You must have a grand name...
Therefore, I got rid of my name.
Go! Keep moving!
Y-Yes sir!
If I'm on a path of no return...
...I'll get rid of everything I've ever received from God.
I don't have to act tough, right?
Tsuyogaranakute iindane
The scribbling someone made...
Dareka ga kaitetta
On the wall, of a flower is swaying.
Kabe no rakugaki no hana ga yureru
No one knows their true selves.
Jibunrashisa nante dermo wakaranaiyo
Even though we both lose and gain
Nagai nagai michi no tochuu de
By embarking on this long, long path,
Nakushitari hirottari
And though there may be days loneliness strikes and makes us weep...
Kyuu ni samishikunatte naichau hi mo arukedo
Let's transform our tears and pains to stars.
Namida mo itami mo hoshi ni kaeyou
Let's light a candle to illuminate our tomorrow.
Ashita wo terasu akari wo tomosou
And we'll hold our small hands over the fire to create stardust,
Chiisana te kazashite futari de tsukurou
And an eternity that shines so brilliantly.
Hoshikuzu wo tsuyoku hikaru eien wo
Farewells may be unavoidable,
Sayonara itsuka wa kurukamoshirenai
Yet the seasons continue to change obliviously.
Kisetsu wa soredemo meguri megutteku
Even if I lose myself, I'll continue to walk...
Chiisaku mayottemo aruiteku
Walk by your side.
Kimi to aruiteku
That's the only thing I'd like to never change.
Sore dake wa kawaranaideiyoune
A sad truth greets Ed, Al, and Winry, who returned to Central with the hopes of a warm reunion.
And the darkness chooses another, new sacrifice.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Footsteps of a
Comrade-in-Arms
Episode 16, Footsteps of a Comrade-in-Arms.
Is it light or darkness...
...within the heart of the man who began to move forward?